Ryan Stinebaugh

🗷 ryanstinebaugh@gmail.com 🔲 7132486095 🛅 in/ryanstinebaugh 🕳 https://ryanstinebaugh.com

SUMMARY

I'm a mechanical engineer with a master's degree in product development who specializes in product design and innovation. Whether the project is physical or digital, I love working in interdisciplinary teams to create products driven by consumer input.

EXPERIENCE

Co-Founder

Beta Keys

April 2019 - July 2019, Pittsburgh, PA

- Designed a modular mechanical gaming keyboard to lower the barrier to entry for professional teams and gaming influencers to sell branded hardware.
- · Prototyped multiple design iterations that would use manufacturing techniques such as injection molding, sheet metal stamping, and ultrasonic plastic welding
- · Managed the relationship with an overseas manufacturer

Product Development Consultant

Smart Hammer Innovation

October 2018 - April 2019, Pittsburgh, PA

- Consulted to Phillips Respironics for two eight-week terms that explored innovative technologies and markets for sleep and respiratory care
- · Conducted customer research, created personas, and developed low-fidelity prototypes

Project Lead

Pittsburgh Knights

June 2018 - April 2019, Pittsburgh, PA

- · Assisted in securing investments from the Pittsburgh Steelers and Wiz Khalifa
- · Led a team to add a new source of revenue for the company
- · Introduced changes to the website to optimize user flow

Process Safety Engineering Intern

Ingenero

June 2016 - July 2016, Houston, TX

- $\cdot \ \, \text{Collected and reported field data on pressure relief valves at Lyondell Basell Polymers Plant}$
- \cdot Learned to read P&ID's and isometric drawings to work independently on the plant
- \cdot Sorted through collected data to create infographics for client presentation

PROJECTS

Wireless Piezoelectric Mechanical Keyboard

- · Won most innovative design at CMU's Mechanical Engineering Spring 2018 Design Expo
- · Designed a keyboard that harnessed energy from key presses to increase battery life
- \cdot Used FDM and SLS 3D printing to prototype and iterate towards a final design
- \cdot Derived and selected the optimal materials for the final product concept through a translation and screening process

Toaster Redesign

- \cdot Disassembled a Proctor Silex Toaster and recorded each part's function and assembly step
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Designed a concept to aster that uses 39 fewer parts and 17 fewer assembly steps

EDUCATION

Master of Integrated Innovation for Products and Services

Carnegie Mellon University · Pittsburgh, PA · 2019 · 3.89 GPA

Bachelors of Science in Mechanical Engineering

Minor in the Mechanical Behavior of Materials · Minor in Innovation & Entrepreneurship · Carnegie Mellon University

· Pittsburgh, PA · 2018 · 3.23 GPA

SKILLS

Software: SolidWorks, Autodesk Inventor, Adobe Photoshop

Prototyping: 3D Printing, Laser Cutting, CNC Mill, Lathes, Drill Press, Band Saw

Coding: MATLAB, HTML, Javascript, CSS, NodeJs, MongoDB, React, Meteor